Matthew Young

🗣 Foster City, California 🔤 y.matt12@gmail.com 🛅 linkedin.com/in/matthew-young-07 📤 matthewyoung777.gitlab.io/portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full-stack software engineer with experience in Python, JavaScript, and Java. Skilled in back-end development using Node.js, Django, Fast API, and PostgreSQL, as well as front-end development with React.js. Experienced in system design using Docker and microservices.

SKILLS

Technical Skills: JavaScript, Python, Java, Django, Fast API, Docker, React.js, Node.js, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Git, Gitlab, Heroku Industry Knowledge: Agile Methodologies, Software Engineering, Algorithms, Unit Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Analysis, Data Science Interpersonal Skills: Teamwork, Communication, Problem solving, Adaptability, Quick Learning, Leadership

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern

Networky.ai

October 2023 - Present, Palo Alto, CA

- · Ensured quality of the training data set for Machine Learning models, by reducing the amount of missing data from 50% to 20% for the training set.
- · Built pipeline integrating transactional text message notifications for e-commerce platform to increase user feedback by 40%.
- · Developed a backend API integrating CrunchBase API to populate training data and drive recommendation algorithm.

Autonomous Vehicle Test Specialist

Cruise

July 2021 - July 2022, San Francisco, CA

- · Increased drivable testing zones by 50% through lane and route mapping techniques.
- · Pinpointed and communicated problematic drive behavior data with engineers to reduce driving error frequency by 30%.
- · Trained fleet operators introducing new techniques for vehicle testing which increased driverless mileage accumulation by 100%.

PROJECTS

FitHub

September 2023 - Present

- · Leading a small team designing and developing a mobile-first Fitness accountability app helping people reach their fitness goals.
- · Conducted competitive analysis of market leading alternatives to drive feature selection and product differentiation.
- · Designed data model architecture for a MongoDB database for improved API response times up to 100ms.
- $\cdot \ \text{Implemented a RESTful API using Node.} \text{js to extract and update data in a MongoDB database.}$

Paper Stonks

 $Hack reactor \cdot https://gitlab.com/apex-legends1/paper-stonks \cdot October 2022 - December 2022$

- · Developed a web-based mock stock trading application simulating investment portfolios and stock trading using real-time stock price data.
- · Orchestrated the creation of a highly scalable and secure REST API powered by Fast API to facilitate seamless data access.
- $\cdot \text{Crafted engaging and interactive user interfaces using React.js, integrated with real-time stock data visualization through Chart.js. \\$
- · Spearheaded the implementation of Docker-based microservice architectures for efficient deployment and scalability.
- $\cdot \ \text{Developed GitLab CI/CD automation pipeline while leading a 5-member team to meet project goals}.$

Car Car

 $Hack reactor \cdot https://gitlab.com/matthewyoung 777/project-beta \cdot September 2022 - October 2022$

- · Engineered a web app streamlining interactions between a dealership and its clientele, inventory tracking, vehicle sales, service appointments.
- · Crafted a dynamic and user-friendly front-end UI with React.js, focusing on the appointment microservice for enhanced user engagement.
- $\cdot \text{ Implemented a robust RESTful API for seamless data access within the appointment microservice with Django.}\\$
- · Held Scrum of scrums for discussing daily progress and sprint goals amongst the team, collaborating with Git version control.
- $\cdot \ Designed \ and \ executed \ a \ scalable \ data \ model \ and \ microservices \ structure, \ with \ Django \ and \ Docker \ for \ performance \ and \ deployment \ efficiency.$

EDUCATION

Software Engineering

Hack Reactor · San Francisco, CA · November 2022

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Economics

University of Washington · Seattle, WA · 2019

· Dean's List recognition for 7 quarters

CERTIFICATIONS

SQL for Data Science

Coursera · 2019